Guide to the Carl Van Vechten Papers Relating to African American Arts and Letters
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Carl Van Vechten Papers Relating to African American Arts and Letters
1800-1971
JWJ MSS 1050
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
49.1
(76 boxes) + 3 art and 2 broadsides
The Carl Van Vechten Papers Relating to African-American Arts and Letters include correspondence, writings, photographs and artwork documenting Van Vechten's interest in and involvement with black artists, writers, and social activists.
Van Vechten, Carl, 1880-1964
Carl Van Vechten
Carl Van Vechten was a writer, photographer, collector, and patron of the arts. Born in Cedar Rapids, Iowa, on June 17, 1880, Van Vechten developed an early interest in literature and the fine and performing arts. He attended the University of Chicago, and wrote for several Chicago newspapers before moving to New York City in 1906. Over the next five decades he established himself as a journalist, critic, novelist, photographer, and cultural icon. He wrote music, dance, and theater reviews in New York and Paris for The New York Times and The New York Press, and for magazines and journals including Trend, Vanity Fair, Crisis, New Republic, and Esquire. He authored numerous books including, Music After the Great War (1915), The Tiger in the House (1920), Peter Whiffle: His Life and Works (1922), The Blind-Bow Boy (1923), The Tattooed Countess (1924), Firecrackers (1925), Nigger Heaven (1926), Spider Boy (1928), Parties (1930), and Sacred and Profane Memories (1932), most of which were published by Alfred A. Knopf.
His 1907 marriage to Ann Snyder, a friend since his youth in Cedar Rapids, ended in divorce in 1912. On October 21, 1914 he married Fania Marinoff, an actress who had immigrated to the United States as a child from Russia. They were married for fifty years. A family inheritance received in 1927 provided Van Vechten with the means to support himself and Fania, and freed him to pursue his interests without financial constraints. During the 1920s, Van Vechten was introduced to members of the artistic and cultural movement that would become known as the Harlem Renaissance. He enjoyed frequenting the clubs, restaurants, and salons of Harlem, and he began to develop friendships among members of the Black community. His 1926 novel, Nigger Heaven, was inspired by his visits to Harlem and its residents.
Beginning in the early 1930s Van Vechten devoted much of his time to photography. In his home studio he produced hundreds of photographic portraits of his friends and acquaintances, as well as other world figures whom he photographed by invitation and by recommendations from mutual friends. He and Fania developed a large multicultural network of friends and acquaintances in New York, throughout the United States, and abroad. The Van Vechten apartment became a meeting place for established and developing writers, visual and performing artists, publishers, educators, social activists, and others. Throughout his life Van Vechten developed close friendships with women as well as intimate relationships with men.
As a collector, Van Vechten acquired important collections of books and manuscripts, particularly those relating to African-American arts and literature. In 1941, he established the James Weldon Johnson Memorial Collection of Negro Arts and Letters at Yale University, in honor of the writer and close friend who had died in 1938. In 1947, Van Vechten established the Anna Marble-Pollock Collection of Books about Cats at Yale. He also gave to Yale additional individual books and manuscripts, as well as a large group of his personal papers. He established and/or donated material to collections at other institutions including Fisk University, Howard University, the University of New Mexico, and the New York Public Library (including personal papers dating from 1833 to 1965). Carl Van Vechten died in New York City on December 22, 1964.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Carl Van Vechten and Fania Marinoff, 1941-1971.
Scope and Contents
The Carl Van Vechten Papers Relating to African-American Arts and Letters include correspondence, writings, photographs and artwork documenting Van Vechten's interest in and involvement with Black artists, writers, and social activists.
Conditions Governing Access
Series I. Correspondence, Series II. Writings, and Series III, Art is open for research. As additional series are processed they will be opened to researchers. For additional information contact the processing archivists.
Box 50 is for research use only, and may not be duplicated.
Boxes 80-81: Restricted fragile material. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Arrangement
Organized into three series: I. Correspondence, 1914-1971. II. Writings,1925-1964. III. Art, 1800-1956.
Fania Marinoff (1890-1971)
Fania Marinoff was born in Odessa, Russia on March 20, 1890, and came to the United States as a child with her family in the mid-1890s. After her family settled in Boston, Fania moved with her older brothers to Denver, Colorado. She began her stage career as a child in Denver, and toured with a stock company before establishing a career in New York City. She married Carl Van Vechten in 1914. Her performance as Ariel in the tercentenary revival of The Tempest in 1916 was highly praised. On Broadway she acted in productions including Arms and the Man (1915), The Streets of New York (1931), The Pillars of Society (1931), and Antony and Cleopatra (1937). She also performed in The Skin of Our Teeth at the Westport Country Playhouse in 1948. Marinoff appeared in early films including The Unsuspected Isles (1915), The Rise of Jenny Cushing (1917), and Life's Whirlpool (1917), and performed on radio broadcasts and various special stage performances. She performed less frequently after 1940, but maintained friendships with fellow actors, directors, and managers, with whom she corresponded throughout her life. Fania Marinoff died in Englewood, New Jersey on November 16, 1971.
Related Materials
Carl Van Vechten Papers (YCAL MSS 1050). Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Yale University.
Carl Van Vechten Papers. New York Public Library, New York, New York.
African American artists -- 20th Century; African American authors -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Harlem Renaissance; Photographs; Artists -- United States -- 20th Century; Authors -- United States -- 20th Century; Bontemps, Arna, 1902-1973; Dodson, Owen, 1914-1983; Handy, W. C. (William Christopher), 1873-1958; Himes, Chester B., 1909-1984; Holt, Nora Douglas, 1885-1974; Hughes, Langston, 1902-1967; Hurston, Zora Neale, 1891-1960; Jackman, Harold, 1901-1961; Johnson, James Weldon, 1871-1938; Johnson, Grace Nail, 1885-1976; Marinoff, Fania, 1890-1971; Nugent, Bruce, 1906-1987; Peterson, Dorothy; Richer, Clément; Robeson, Eslanda Goode, 1896-1965; Robeson, Paul, 1898-1976; Schuyler, Josephine, 1900-1969; Schuyler, Philippa, 1932-1967; Thomas, Edna, 1885-1974; White, Walter, 1893-1955; Van Vechten, Carl, 1880-1964; Fisk University; Howard University
- Correspondence, 1914-1971; Series I; 26.6; 58 boxes
  Arrangement
  Organized into four subseries: A-Z Correspondence; Copies of Letters in Carl Van Vechten Papers from the New York Public Library; Christmas Cards; and Advertising Cards, Invitations to Clubs, Balls, and Restaurants. The A-Z Correspondence and Copies of Letters from the New York Public Library are arranged alphabetically by correspondent and chronologically within files. The Christmas Cards are arranged by year, then alphabetically by correspondent. The Advertising Cards and Invitations are arranged by size.
  At some point in the past, library staff numbered each incoming letter from some correspondents in pencil. In cases where the numbering did not match the chronological ordering of the letters, current staff chronologically arranged them.
  Scope and Contents
  Series I. Correspondence, documents Carl Van Vechten's friendships and acquaintances with writers, artists, musicians, singers, actors, social activists and other members of the African-American community in New York City, and throughout the United States and abroad. The correspondence, which was formerly called "Letters from Blacks," includes letters sent to Carl Van Vechten and his wife, Fania Marinoff, from Black artists, writers, and social activists, and from individuals corresponding about African-descended people and cultures. As noted in the processing note, decisions regarding the inclusion of correspondents in this collection were made by Van Vechten and curator Donald Gallup as the material was received by the library beginning in the 1940s, and those decisions have guided staff in subsequent processing of the collection.
  The correspondence ranges from single letters to extensive correspondence documenting Van Vechten's relationships with friends and associates over many years. Correspondents include writers James Baldwin, Charles W. Chesnutt, Countee Cullen, Owen Dodson, Chester Himes, Langston Hughes, Zora Neale Hurston, Nella Larsen Imes, James Weldon Johnson, and Richard Wright; composers and performers Marian Anderson, Pearl Bailey, William C. Handy, Nora Holt, J. Rosamond Johnson, Leontyne Price, Paul Robeson and his wife, Eslanda Robeson; artists Richmond Barthé and Aaron Douglas; educators Arna Bontemps, Elmer Samuel Imes, Harold Jackman, and Dorothy Peterson; and social activists Shirley Graham Du Bois, W.E.B. Du Bois, Grace Nail Johnson, Walter White and Roy Wilkins. Van Vechten's philanthropic activities are documented by his correspondence with administrators and staff of institutions to which he donated collections of books, manuscripts, and photographs, including Fisk University, Howard University, Piney Woods Country Life School, and Wadleigh High School, among others, as well as individuals and institutions to which he provided financial support.
  Folder-level scope and contents notes provide descriptions of third-party correspondents, photographs, writings, and other enclosures. In some cases, Van Vechten's drafts and/or carbon copies of his outgoing letters to correspondents are included with the incoming letters. Letters to Fania Marinoff are interfiled with those to Van Vechten; folder-level scope and content notes indicate when an individual's correspondence was sent only to Fania (FM).
  - A-Z Correspondence
    - Abrahams, Peter, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Adams, Alton A., 1951 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Addison, Adele, 1955–1963 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Includes third-party letter from Chicago Symphony Orchestra to Mrs. Frederic W. Upham (1957)
    - Addison, Lloyd E., 1957 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Includes photograph of Addison enclosed with letter to CVV
    - Adelman, Lynn, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - African Aid Committee, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - African-American Students Foundation, Inc., 1959 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Ailey, Alvin, 1955-1964, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Includes a press release (1960) and notes from Ailey written on performance announcements (1961, 1963)
    - Alexander, Lewis, 1926 December 5 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Allen, Betty, 1956-1964, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Includes autograph manuscript note from Miles to CVV written on promotional flyer (1960)
    - Allen, George Leonard, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Allen, Luther, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
      Two-page letter written on verso of photographs of a Black child named Charles
    - Allen, William, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Invitation to the opening of Hotel Cosmopolitan, Los Angeles
    - Allicks, Claudette, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      Relating to the Josephine Baker Day sponsored by the New York N.A.A.C.P.
    - Allied Repertory Players, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Allure, The Magazine for the Women of Color, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - American Society of African Culture, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - American Writers Committee Against Lynching, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      Telegram signed by Lewis Gannett, Walter White, Benjamin Stolbert, and Helen Woodward
    - Anderson, Garland, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Anderson, Marian, 1947–1967 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      Includes third-party correspondence
    - Anna Lucasta cast, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Archer, Osceola, 1945–1962 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Armstrong, Harry, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Arvey, Verna, 1934–1963 (Box 1, Folder 24-25)
      Includes typescript, carbon copy of "Those Who Wait," with words by Verna Arvey and music by William Grant Still, enclosed with letter from Arvey to CVV (1943); photograph of Duncan Still and Judith Still enclosed with letter from Arvey to CVV (1943); typed note, signed, by William Grant Still (1943); typed letter, carbon copy, from Arvey to Donald Windham enclosed with letter from Arvey to CVV (1944); typed press release, mimeograph, regarding the opera Highway I, U.S.A. by Arvey and William Grant Still (1963)
    - Association for the Study of Negro Life and History, Inc., 1959 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Astwood, Alexander Carl, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Atkins, Russell, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Atkinson, Edward, 1942–1964 (Box 1, Folder 29-30)
      Biographical / Historical
      CVV referred to Edward Atkinson as "Edward III"
      Includes a child safety pamphlet, "Peter and the Whiffle-Hound" enclosed with note of 1943 April 9
    - Atlanta University Library. Countee Cullen Memorial Collection, 1943-1963, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
      Includes copies of several lists of gifts from CVV to the Countee Cullen collection and numerous gift acknowledgements
    - Attaway, Ruth, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Austin, Bernia, 1931 April 14 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Bailey, Pearl, 1947-1975, undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
      Includes notes from Bailey written on performance announcements; a proclamation of Pearl Bailey Day in the City of Newport News, Virginia (1974) and a ticket to a Pearl Bailey performance (1974)
      Immediate Source of Acquisition
      Proclamation and ticket, gift of the original recipient, Ida Himes
    - Baker, Corinne, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Baldwin, James, 1956–1964 (Box 2, Folder 36)
      Includes third-party letter regarding photograph of Baldwin (1956) and form letters from civil rights organizations written under Baldwin's signature (1963-1964)
    - Ballet Americana, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Banks, William Augustus, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 38)
      Includes two cards advertising "Beyond the Rockies" by William Augustus Banks, Dorrance and Co., Publishers, Philadelphia, PA
    - Bardolph, Richard, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 39)
      Includes typed mimeographed lists of "Negroes Known to Be Listed " in volumes of Who's Who in America published between 1936 and 1955
    - Barnett, Etta Moten, 1934 June 13 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Barthé, Richmond, 1937-1970, undated (Box 2, Folder 41-42)
    - Baschat, F., undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Bass, George Houston, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Bass, Maudelle, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Beane, Reginald, 1938–1964 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Bearden, R. Howard, 1944; 1950 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Bearden, Romare, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Beaumont, Jake L., 1950 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Beaver, Joseph T., 1958–1959 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Belafonte, Harry, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Belinsky, Isai, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Bell, Mary A., 1937-1939, undated (Box 2, Folder 53)
      Includes original and typed transcripts of letters from Bell to Mark Lutz (1938-1939); and typescript essay about Mary Bell by Lutz (1938)
    - Bender, Harold H. (Harold Herman), 1935 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Benedusi, Robert, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Bennett, Gwendolyn, 1926, undated (Box 2, Folder 56)
      Includes letter of 1926 November 15 on letterhead for the journal Fire!! Devoted to Younger Negro Artists
    - Bentley, Gladys, 1944, undated (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Bernheardt, Edward, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Berry, Blanche, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Bethune, Mary Jane McLeod, 1943-1964, undated (Box 2, Folder 60)
      Includes invitations to benefits and dinners held in Bethune's honor
    - Black, Julian, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Blackwell, Frances, 1958; 1961; undated (Box 2, Folder 62)
      Includes photograph of Lisa Mia Blackwell
    - Blanton, J. E., 1936 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Bledsoe, Jules, 1925–1939 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Blue, Ila Jacuith, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Bolling, Leslie Garland, 1933–1939 (Box 3, Folder 66)
      Includes third-party letters from Thomas Parker, Richmond Academy of Arts (1934); Kathryn B. Greywacz, New Jersey State Museum (1935); William D. Cox (1935, 1937); and Mark Lutz (1939)
    - Bonds, Caska, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Bonds, Margaret, 1956-1963, undated (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Bontemps, Arna, 1939–1965 (Box 3, Folder 69-72)
      Includes original and carbon copies of letters to and/or from Mrs. James Weldon Johnson (1945); Charles S. Johnson (1945); John W. Work (1953); Alberta (Mrs. Arna) Bontemps (1947); Harry E. von Bergen (1956); May Davenport Seymour, Museum of the City of New York (1958); Herman A. Schlinder (1960); Frank E. Fenner, Field Enterprises Educational Corporation (1963); Wayne D. Shirley, International Inventory of Musical Sources (1964); and invitations to various events of the James Weldon Johnson Literary Guild (1940, 1950) and Friends of Countee Cullen (1947)
    - Bosley, Roberta, 1940–1962 (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - Bosworth, Hobart, 1916 May 10 (Box 3, Folder 74)
      Letter to FM
    - Boutté, Etna Rochon, 1928; undated (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - Bowles, Minnie Redmond, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 76)
      Related Materials
      See also: Fisk University Library, Florine Stettheimer Memorial Library of Books about the Fine Arts
    - Boyd, Carroll, 1943 October 10 (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - Braithwaite, William Stanley, 1947; 1962 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - Brall, Ruth, 1954 September 16 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Brandstadt, W.G., 1926 (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - Brawley, Benjamin Grifith, 1926 April 25 (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - Brewer, John Mason, 1947–1957 (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - Brice, Carol, 1947–1963 (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - Bricktop, 1920-1960, undated (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - Brierre, Jean F., 1951 April 17 (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - Brooks, Morris, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - Brown, Debria, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - Brown, Esther, 1959–1963 (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - Brown, Gabriel, 1936; 1939 (Box 3, Folder 89)
    - Brown, H.L., 1935 July 17 (Box 4, Folder 90)
    - Brown, John S., Jr., 1944 August 21 (Box 4, Folder 91)
    - Browne, Marie Joe, 1941–1942 (Box 4, Folder 92)
    - Bruce, Roscoe Conkling, 1926 June 22 (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - Bryant, Alzonia I., 1943 November 18 (Box 4, Folder 94)
    - Buckmaster, Henrietta, undated (Box 4, Folder 95)
    - Bunche, Ralph J. (Ralph Johnson), 1951 July 5 (Box 4, Folder 96)
    - Burdett, Madeline M., 1926 October 25 (Box 4, Folder 97)
    - Burleigh, H.T. (Harry Thacker), 1942 January 5 (Box 4, Folder 98)
    - Burley, Dan, 1948–1957 (Box 4, Folder 99)
      Includes cancelled check to Burley from CVV (1954)
    - Burley, Grace Taylor, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 100)
    - Cabaniss, Virgil, 1950 December 12 (Box 4, Folder 101)
    - Callender, Agatha Glasgow, 1963 [January?] (Box 4, Folder 102)
    - Campbell, Brun, 1948; 1950 (Box 4, Folder 103)
    - Campbell, Dick, 1961–1962 (Box 4, Folder 104)
    - Campbell, E. Simms (Elmer Simms), 1929 December 22 (Box 4, Folder 105)
    - Cannon, Poppy, 1955–1960 (Box 4, Folder 106)
    - Carlen, Robert, 1943; 1950 (Box 4, Folder 107)
    - Carlis, John, 1958–1964 (Box 4, Folder 108)
    - Carrington, Glenn, 1942–1964 (Box 4, Folder 109-110)
      Includes lists of recordings by Ethel Waters (1943, 1950) and postcard photographs by Carrington (1946-1948)
    - Carroll, Diahann, 1955-1962, undated (Box 4, Folder 111)
    - Carter, Herman Jefferson Davis, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 112)
    - Carter, William J., 1934; 1953 (Box 4, Folder 113)
    - Casals, Pablo, 1962 May 25 (Box 4, Folder 114)
      Letter co-signed by Warner Lawson
    - Cassilly, Thomas A., 1951 February 28 (Box 4, Folder 115)
    - Castleberry, Ann C., undated (Box 4, Folder 116)
    - Cayton, Horace R. (Horace Roscoe), 1947–1948 (Box 4, Folder 117)
    - Ceough, Richard, 1943–1944 (Box 4, Folder 118)
      Includes typed suggested rewrites for final paragraph of CVV's article for Theatre Annual (1943)
    - Chesnutt, Charles W. (Charles Waddell), 1926–1932 (Box 4, Folder 119)
      See also: Box 50
    - Chesnutt, Helen M., 1946–1952 (Box 4, Folder 120)
      Includes typed mimeograph description of the Charles W. Chesnutt Collection, Fisk University Library (1952)
    - Chicago Defender, 1927; 1949 (Box 4, Folder 121)
    - Clark, Carolyn
      See: Hughes, Carrie
    - Clark, Edgar Rogie, 1949 June 4 (Box 4, Folder 122)
    - Cleveland, Ladybird, 1954; 1959 (Box 4, Folder 123)
    - Cleveland (Ohio). Deptartment of Public Health and Welfare, 1954 September 22 (Box 4, Folder 124)
    - Cobb, Naomi R., 1944 July 20 (Box 4, Folder 125)
    - Cochran, A. Myron, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 126)
    - Coffee Concerts (New York), 1958–1963 (Box 4, Folder 127)
      Letters signed by Raoul Abdul
    - Cole, Louis, 1929–1932 (Box 4, Folder 128)
    - Coleman, Gilbert B., 1960 August 26 (Box 4, Folder 129)
    - Coleman, Leo, 1947 November 19 (Box 4, Folder 130)
    - Coles, Sallie, 1935 March 4 (Box 4, Folder 131)
    - Collins, Durward, 1962 October 7 (Box 4, Folder 132)
    - Collins, Janet, 1944-1955, undated (Box 4, Folder 133)
    - Collins, Leslie M., 1945–1946 (Box 4, Folder 134)
    - Collins, Z., 1953 March 19 (Box 4, Folder 135)
    - Collymore, Frank A., 1957 (Box 4, Folder 136)
    - Cook, Will Marion, 1927 October 25 (Box 4, Folder 137)
    - Cortor, Eldzier, [1958?] (Box 4, Folder 138)
    - Cottingham, Clive, 1950–1962 (Box 4, Folder 139)
      Includes note from Parke-Bernet Galleries to Cottingham (1950) and typed note from Harold Jackman (1950)
    - Cowl, Carl, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 140)
    - Creswell, Pearl S., 1950–1964 (Box 5, Folder 141)
      Typed mimeograph description of exhibit at the Carl Van Vechten Gallery, Fisk University, enclosed with letter of 1956 August 16
    - The Crisis, 1944–1957 (Box 5, Folder 142)
    - Crump, Robert A., 1925 (Box 5, Folder 143)
    - Cullen, Countee, 1925–1957 (Box 5, Folder 144-145)
    - Cuney, William Waring, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 146)
      Includes V-mail letters
    - D. Appleton-Century Company, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 147)
    - Dancecraft, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 148)
      Printed invitation to opening of Dancecraft's studios with autograph note signed "B"
    - Daniel, Albert E., 1951 March 28 (Box 5, Folder 149)
    - Daniels, Jimmie, 1931-1970, undated (Box 5, Folder 150)
    - Darrow, Carl
      See: White, Carl Darrow
    - Davis, Belle, 1933-1964, undated (Box 5, Folder 151)
      Includes letters written on behalf of the National Health Circle for Colored People, Inc., and CVV's cancelled check to the organization
    - Davis, Ellabelle, 1947 April 14 (Box 5, Folder 152)
    - Davis, Frank Marshall, 1948 October 8 (Box 5, Folder 153)
    - Davis, James E., 1942–1943 (Box 5, Folder 154)
    - Davis, Jefferson D., 1948 July 15 (Box 5, Folder 155)
    - Davis, Malcolm G., 1951 May 28 (Box 5, Folder 156)
    - Davis, Robert A., 1944 (Box 5, Folder 157)
    - Davis, Sammy, Jr., 1957 June 15 (Box 5, Folder 158)
      Form letter on behalf of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People financial crisis accompanied by donation card and self-addressed envelope
    - Davy, Gloria, 1958 September 29 (Box 5, Folder 159)
    - Dawson, William L. (William Levi), 1935; 1942 (Box 5, Folder 160)
    - Day, Carita, 1942–1951 (Box 5, Folder 161)